For many of us, the relationship we have with sugar is love at first taste, and that love usually lasts a lifetime.
对我们许多人来说，与糖的关系是一见钟情的爱，而这种爱通常会持续一生。
But what price do we have to pay for this truly addictive, sugary love?
但我们要为这种真正令人上瘾的甜蜜之爱付出什么代价呢？
Rotten teeth?
蛀牙？
Heavier bodies?
更肥胖的身体？
Raised blood sugar levels?
高血糖？
Or even type 2 diabetes?
甚至2型糖尿病？
Time to quit perhaps?
也许是时候戒糖了？
Easier said than done.
说起来容易做起来难。
What’s the alternative?
有什么替代品呢？
Many would suggest using sweeteners as a substitute.
许多人会建议使用甜味剂作为替代品。
But are sweeteners healthier than sugar?
但甜味剂比糖更健康吗？
Sweeteners are usually low-calorie or calorie-free substances that have a similar taste to sugar.
甜味剂通常是低热量或无热量的物质，味道与糖相似。
It is estimated that more than a quarter of British households buy artificial sweeteners to help cut their sugar intake.
据估计，超过四分之一的英国家庭购买人造甜味剂以帮助减少糖的摄入量。
The European Food Safety Authority (EFSA) has approved some of the health claimsfood manufacturers have made about sweeteners such as xylitol, sorbitol and sucralose.
欧洲食品安全局（EFSA）已批准了食品制造商对木糖醇、山梨糖醇和三氯蔗糖等甜味剂做出的健康声明。
These include preventing tooth decay and controlling blood sugar levels.
这些声明包括预防蛀牙和控制血糖水平。
According to the National Health Service in the UK, sweeteners are safe to use and are especially helpful for those who are diabetic.
根据英国国家医疗服务体系（NHS），甜味剂可以安全使用，尤其对糖尿病患者有帮助。
Sioned Quirke, a spokesperson for the British Dietetic Association says, “As a dietician, I support and promote the use of sweeteners in cooking and diet."
英国饮食协会发言人西奥内德·奎克（Sioned Quirke）说：“作为一名营养师，我支持并提倡在烹饪和饮食中使用甜味剂。”
She also says that "There is no evidence to suggest that low-calorie sweeteners, such as saccharin, aspartame and sucralose, are harmful or bad for you.”
她还说：“没有证据表明低热量甜味剂，如糖精、阿斯巴甜和三氯蔗糖，对人体健康有害。”
But many have concerns over the long-term effects caused by using sweeteners.
但许多人对使用甜味剂的长期影响表示担忧。
Dr Robert Lustig, author of 'Fat Chance: The Bitter Truth About Sugar' would not endorse sweeteners as an alternative to sugar because, “We have a dearth of data”.
《机会渺茫：关于糖的苦涩真相》一书的作者罗伯特·勒斯蒂格（Robert Lustig）博士不赞同甜味剂作为糖的替代品，因为“我们缺乏数据”。
According to Dr Lustig, organisations like EFSA only require studies which test if something will poison a person in a short period of time, otherwise known as acute toxicity studies.
根据勒斯蒂格博士的说法，像EFSA这样的组织只要求研究某种物质是否会在短时间内毒害人体，也就是急性毒性研究。
But we still don’t know what the long-term effects are.
但我们仍然不知道有什么长期影响。
Dietician Emma Carder says on the NHS Choices website, “While more research is needed, sweeteners continue to have a useful role in offering a sweet taste without adding extra calories.”
营养师艾玛·卡德（Emma Carder）在NHS Choices网站上表示：“虽然需要更多的研究，但甜味剂在提供甜味而不增加额外热量方面仍然具有重要作用。”